LUCAS CALVETTI

Temperley, Buenos Aires, Argentina • +54 9 1151211065 • I.calvetti.dev@gmail.com https://lucascalvetti.github.io/portfolio-frontend/ • https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucas-calvetti/

PROFILE

I am a **Fullstack developer with over 3 years of experience** in web application development. I specialize in JavaScript/TypeScript and have completed a large number of projects. I am very passionate about technology and constantly seek to improve my programming skills and knowledge. I am currently taking an **AWS Practitioner** course to expand my knowledge in **cloud computing**.

FullStack developer - Graduate of Apx.school

EXPERIENCE

Fullstack web developer in Triunfo360

Feb 2024 - Now Remote - Montevideo, Uruguay

- Design and develop attractive user interfaces and APIs using Tailwind, React, HTML, CSS.
- Gained experience in leading and forming developer teams and recruiting.
- Solve both technical and communication problems essential for teamwork.
- Primarily work on the Frontend, where I lead the project team.

FullStack Developer career

Apx.school Mar 2021 - Nov 2023

- I learned basic web fundamentals like **DOM**, **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, use of **REST APIs**, **web hosting**, **and HTTP/HTTPS protocols**.
- I also delved into more advanced fundamentals such as using libraries and frameworks like React, Express, Node.js, and Next.js (SSR and ISR) among others, TypeScript, managing SQL, NoSQL, and Realtime Databases (PostgreSQL and Google Firebase), data encryption, OAuth, JWT, CI/CD deployment, website optimization with tools like Webpack, Parcel, Lazy Loading, and Lighthouse, Git, Testing (unit tests with AVA), and payment gateway integration with MercadoPago, search databases and geolocation with Algolia.
- Furthermore, I specialized in methodologies such as Mobile First, MVC, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Pair Programming, and Design Thinking.
- I have created multiple projects using the mentioned technologies and methodologies, some of which can be found in my portfolio at https://lucascalvetti.github.io/portfoliofrontend/

EDUCATION

Apx school FullStack Developer career

AWS cloud computing course at Coderhouse (In progress)

Mar 2021 - Nov 2023 Jul 2024 - Now

IDIOMAS

Spanish: Native

English: B2 (Upper Intermediate)

HARD SKILLS

- DOM
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- API REST
- · Web hosting
- HTTP/HTTPS Protocols
- React
- Express
- Node.js
- Next.js
- Tailwind
- TypeScript
- SQL (PostgreSQL with sequelize)
- NoSQL (Google Firebase)
- Realtime Database
- OAuth
- JWT (JSON Web Tokens)
- Deploy CI/CD
- Webpack
- Parcel
- Lazy Loading
- Lighthouse
- Git
- Unit Test with AVA
- Mobile First
- MVC
- Agile
- Scrum (Trello)
- Mercadopago (Payment gateway)
- Github
- Algolia

SOFT SKILLS

- Management skills
- · Communication skills
- Teaching experience (Former teacher)
- · Critical thinking
- · Problem-solving skills
- Enthusiasm
- Open-mindedness
- · Patience and empathy
- Versatility
- Quick learner
- · Autonomy in projects
- · Recruiting experience
- Design Thinking
- · Technical and communication problem-solving
- Teamwork
- · Effective communication
- Adaptability